hi my name is Tanaka Akiyama
and I'm going to present our paper
which explores stigma and service robots
as our world increasingly integrates service
robots into various facets of daily life
it's crucial to reassess their purpose and user base
today we'll delve into a critical aspect
that's often overlooked
stigma and the design of service robots
let's first distinguish between assistive
and service robots
assistive robots cater to specific user groups
such as elderly care
or educational assistance for children with autism
on the other hand
service robots provide assistive functionality
but are designed for communal use
serving diverse users
regardless of their abilities
we can think of service robots as public facing
robots that have assistive features
that's why it's important to look at stigma
as it is a prominent challenge regarding
the acceptance of assistive technology
stigma manifests in various forms
consider this scenario
a person is using a robot for grocery shopping
from an observer standpoint
they might perceive the user as helpless
reflecting perceived stigma
conversely the user might experience self stigma
fearing judgment
and questioning their capabilities
both forms of stigma have
the potential to significantly influence the acceptance
usability and effectiveness of service robots
stigma link to the utilization of assistive technology
or robots has been well documented
existing literature highlights how
older adults often perceive the use of assistive robots
as a symbol of dependency
which they consider an insurmountable barrier to
accepting robots
while exploring
established frameworks for the technology acceptance
such as the Technology Acceptance model
it's notable that stigma is not accounted for
although it is a significant factor
progress has been made with
the inclusion of a stigma category in the Unified
Theory of acceptance and use of technology
however there's still room for refinement
particularly in differentiating between self stigma
and perceived stigma
psychology does
offer more comprehensive methods for evaluating stigma
and investigating their relevance to robotics and HRI
is warranted
so how can we address the stigma surrounding robot use
one strategy is universal design
aiming to make systems
accessible to individuals with diverse abilities
this approach reduces
the necessity for specialized adaptations
and normalizes the use of service robots
another approach involves integrating robots
inconspicuously into the environment
while this tactic addresses perceived stigma
it may not effectively tackle
the primary issue of self stigma
which holds significant
importance for technology adoption
additionally
marketing strategies have been
proposed to destigmatize images
of assistive robotics
particularly targeting older adults
to increase acceptance
nevertheless
future research is essential to assess the
effectiveness of these approaches in closing
we've identified crucial areas for exploration
researchers should focus on investigating how service
robots can be
effectively designed to cater to a diverse user group
they should also quantify
the degree of stigma associated with service robots
we should develop
standardized metrics to evaluate stigma upon robot use
and explore optimal strategies for reducing stigma
by investigating these questions
we can pave the way for a more inclusive
and accepting society
where service robots fulfill their promise
of enhancing quality of life
in addressing societal needs