Assistive technology is worthless if it is not accessible.
This presentation is meant to raise awareness of the complexities of connected assistive technologies.
I explore these through the lens of a Bluetooth-enabled hearing aid.
Bluetooth-enabled hearing aids have many features, including:
Preset programs optimized for hearing in different environments
Monitoring and tracking hearing aid usage and physical activities
Fall detection with automatic text alerts sent to a designated contact list
Spoken language translated to a preferred target language
Headset capabilities enabling clear calls and streamed content like music, podcasts and audio books.
All this technology is great when the Bluetooth connectivity works.
However, when it doesn't, failures in connectivity become a common roadblock to full feature accessibility.
Bluetooth failures are usually connected to software or firmware updates.
They can also be caused by interference from other devices or from switching from Wi-Fi to cellular data.
For someone not familiar with technology, fixing connectivity issues can be a tedious, confusing process.
Sometimes reconnection can involve almost 20 steps.
Some people just give up and never enjoy the full capabilities of their hearing aids.
Fixing connectivity issues should not be this hard.
Sometimes the accessibility issues caused by connectivity issues are inconvenient.
Conversations may not be as clear.
Programs that allow optimization of sound settings are no longer available.
There is no more streaming of content to one's hearing aids, and hearing and health monitoring no longer works.
Sometimes the consequences are dangerous.
Disconnection to a navigation aid while driving means you are no longer able to hear the driving directions. You could get lost in an unfamiliar place.
Unreliable features like fall detection give false expectations of safety.
If a user falls, a fall alert will no longer be sent to their designated contact list.
Inaccessible features, no matter how wonderful, do no one any good.
When designing assistive technology, there are four important metrics to consider.
Reliability. A product needs to behave as expected.
Availability. As users of assistive technology are often dependent on it, it must be operational when they need it.
Serviceability. Maintaining or fixing a product should be simple, not a 20-step process.
Accessibility. If a person cannot understand how to use a product, it is not accessible.
When designing new technologies, developers need to:
Recognize that most users lack the background to navigate technology hiccups.
They need to employ non-tech savvy testers before product rollouts and coordinate software updates that affect device connectivity.
But most importantly, they need to remember that people rely on their products to work when needed.