Hi, I'm Andrew Hundt and I'm going to talk about
our paper: Love, Joy and Autism Robots: A
Metareview and Provocatype with myself Andrew
Hundt, Gabrielle Ohlson, Pieter Wolfert, Lux
Miranda, Sophia Zhu, and Katie Winkle as authors.
We review a set of autism reviews and find that
current autism robot research tends to risk
harming autistic people, lack measures of harmful
impacts, use deficit language, lack rigor and be
outdated. Interventions are autistic people's
second to lowest research priority, yet they
dominate autism robot research. And here we're
comparing current autism research against autism
robot research. So let's take an example, eye
contact training. That's the most common robot
intervention, it's uncomfortable or even painful
for many. And among autism interventions, which
was already ranked second to last. Eye contact is
also ranked, within interventions, second to last.
So it's at the bottom of the bottom of the list
here, it's the most common intervention, there's
known negative health impacts of camouflaging,
which includes eye contact, and that means it's
not consistent with the benefits and amorphous non
maleficence principles required for most human
subjects research. So, with this in mind, we
create a provocative, creative design provocation
for a robot to fix neurotypical spectrum disorder,
suffers deficits. So we restate research findings
from a perspective where autistic strengths are
the default. And this iterates on a strategy for
say swapping names in a paper switch the
participant to researcher and if the candidate
sounds like it would be offensive about you, then
that's something to avoid. And reasons why this
matters, an example, is the way that neurotypical
peers are less willing to interact with those with
autism, based on thin slice judgments, so even
just seeing them for a brief period of time. And
so we go over some common set signs of
neurotypical spectrum disorder, which is
characterized by various deficits and
difficulties, like understanding direct
communication with the tendency to invent implied
content that isn't present, and difficulty with
avoiding negative assumptions and judgments about
harmlessly divergent people and behaviors. But, we
then took the time to think about that provoca
type, and realize that this sort of framing is
really problematic. And really, the risk is too
high of working from that sort of angle, so we
decided to end the project accordingly, and that's
a robot provacatype is to end the project when
it's appropriate to do so. Then we also recommend
pursuing top research priorities for autistic
people that's includes mental health and well
being identifying and diagnosing autistic people
plus post diagnostic support, services and support
across the lifespan across including social care
and health care. Guess what, people remain
autistic if they turn 18, knowledge and attitudes
towards autistic people, and how we view and
communicate about autism and the deficit language
we use and keep to the provocative type sort of
conveys how prevailing attitudes are problematic
and how they could change too, and the rest of the
paper goes in about how it could change to be
better. Then we also make recommendations here is
a selection: refocus on autistic led research
parties and resources. That's anything from
autistic participants all the way up through
artistic researchers. Use inclusive language,
address individual artistic environmental needs.
Some people are sensory seeking. Some people are
sensory avoidant, or have sensory sensitivities,
those vary per autistic individual and those need
to be respected. And the autistic SPACE framework
is a paper published last year, that is a really
useful resource to guide safer research
environments. It focuses on medicine, but a lot of
the knowledge embedded there is transferable. Then
there's a whole bunch of other key info in the
paper, some disability terminology, historical
events, and more details about our review of
autism robot reviews, a summary of essential
current autism research, details about autistic
priorities, the robot provoca type and
recommendations and guidance about those findings.
papers that researchers should read if you're
doing autism research, especially autism, robot
research, and changes that should be made into
autism robot projects and policies. And that's a
brief summary of our paper! We hope you enjoy it!
Thanks a lot for joining us!