Hello, and very warm welcome from my side.
My name is Katharina Schmermbeck, and I'm very happy to talk a bit about our initiative,
which we can present at the A3DE workshop at the HRI
conference in Boulder of this year.
So what is our initiative about?  We try to bring more inclusion
in our region the city of Innsbruck by bringing together different
stakeholders and the community to the Design and Co-design of assistive technologies.
We offer different co-design lectures within bachelor's
as well as Masters Degree. The Bachelor's degree course is in the
field of engineering whlle the Master's course is open to all students, so an
an interdisciplinary course where students work together with people
with disabilities on AT projects.
We combine the teaching and research with a community
transfer which we do by offering and organizing a regular open Forum,
which happens in the city and here people can come together and
talk about Assistive Technologies, talk about solutions, experiences they made
because we felt that a lot of people also don't know what is happening on the market.
They might have not seen any solutions others have
seen and so we try to bring together ideas and exchange.
In the courses,
however, we built Assistive Technologies with students and people with disabilities.
They form groups and build Assistive Technologies
while always meeting regularly over the whole semester.
Now, one year after practice,
we looked into its impact on the development of Assistive Technologies.
And also on the mitigation of ableism.
You can look up all the results here on the poster where I also marked who
from the people I interviewed were having the same opinion on different topics.
What we concluded is that we can meet individual requirements
when developing Assistive Technologies together in these expert teams in the courses.
However, it's especially the short amount of time in one semester
and grading and also knowledge and background constraints
of students necessitate that we continue developments also in upcoming semesters.
What we also saw is that the initiative has very positive influence
on participants and their views and attitudes towards people with
disabilities because a lot of the students and also other participants
were never really in contact with people with disabilities so that could
learn a lot and however,
we see that only few people participate and for a big change,
we believe that it's very important to offer these courses also
as a definite part in the university and
also in multiple degrees and also courses where all students need to go.
If you have any questions,
please don't hesitate to contact us, visit our
website and we're happy to answer all of your questions.